ANAND SUBRAMANIAM

London, United Kingdom

Working in marketing and PR as a Video Producer.

asubramaniam.com linkedin.com/in/anand-s Multimedia and Arts Technology graduate with a first class honours, experienced in a range of creative technologies. Previously at Microsoft

working with games, Windows 10 and HoloLens.

anand.subra@hotmail.com 07983745129 Seeking opportunities to create highly compelling and engaging video content.

EXPERIENCE

Four

Video Producer

Communications Nov 2016 - til date Production of both long and short form content across a range of industries, predominantly for use on clients' social media channels. Also coded HTML emails and product landing pages.

Queen Mary **University of London** June 2015 - Sept 2015

Freelance Filmmaker

Short docu-film based on student experiences during their internships in the technology industry. Direction, management and production of video (from pre to post) — https://youtu.be/Kku7Xf7HFfo

Microsoft Be Your Future

Director of Video

Sept 2014 - June 2015

Management and production of video content (from pre to post). Liaised with other blog team members to help market/promote internship, graduate and apprenticeship opportunities.

EDUCATION

Queen Mary **University of London** BSc(Eng) Multimedia & Arts Technology

School of Electronic Engineering and Computer Science

Sept 2012 - June 2016

First-class with honours, with Industrial Experience at Microsoft

SKILLS

Video

Expert with Adobe Premiere Pro, sound experience with Adobe After Effects and Apple Final Cut Pro. Video production (pre to post), photography.

Audio/Graphics

Apple Logic Pro, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator. Audio recording/production, sound design, visual design.

Equipment

Experienced with Sony A7sii, Sony FS5, Canon 5Dmiii camera systems. Own a Lumix GH5. Experienced with microphones (shotgun/lapel) and LED lighting panels.

Code

HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, open-source hardware (Arduino/BITalino), Processing, NodeJS, Python (Django).

Misc

Piano, skateboarding, bubble tea making

Languages

English, Hindi, Gujarati, Tamil

PERSONAL PROJECTS

YouTube Production and uploading of regular videos exploring filmmaking

Experiments techniques and narrative concepts.

Screenplay Work in progress. Minimalist screenplay compositing tool built using web

Scriptwriting web app technologies.

Knock A private electronic doorbell system using a custom API, an Arduino

Digital doorbell board, the Processing IDE and web technologies.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Graduation Awarded the 'Multimedia and Arts Technology Finalist prize for

Outstanding Achievement'.

Undergraduate dissertation Achieved 90%. Submitted the paper for 2017, titled "Mood Visualiser:

augmented music visualisation gauging audience arousal".

REFERENCES

Available upon request.